JONATHAN WEBER

WEB DEVELOPER

(760) 419-0734

□ Jonweber09@gmail.com

🧿 Vista, CA

https://jonweberportfol.io

in Jonweber09

JayWebz

7+ years experienced, dynamic, and diligent Front-end Web Developer with an exemplary history of building, implementing, updating, and managing websites and web applications using objectoriented best practices, usercentric design, and modern programming tools and languages. Such work includes building games, a music playlist-generation web app, and static and dynamic responsive websites. Wellversed in Single-Page Applications, using CMS', and connecting APIs to Web Uls.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web tech & frameworks - HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Redux Scripting - JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, Python

Debug: Chrome, Firefox

Application/Web Server: Apache

(XAMPP), Webpack

Versioning/Other tools: Git, Mercurial, JIRA, Beanstalk, Sourcetree, Postman

Deployment Tools: Jenkins,

Docker, Surge

MANAGERIAL SKILLS

Front-end Development Agile Method Code Optimization **UI** Enhancement Stakeholder MGMT **Documentation & Reporting**

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NTN Buzztime, Inc. » Web Developer

09/2013 - PRESENT 12/2016 - PRESENT

- > Develop UI/UX across several single-page applications and websites while managing the data interchange between servers and users using RESTful/SOAP API calls via GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE http requests.
- > Experienced with Node.js and NPM packages such as nodesass, react-router-dom, yaml-loader, post-css-cli, react-recaptcha, axios, express, react-redux, google-maps-react, and more.
- > Translate UI/UX design wireframes into coded features to build and enhance overall architecture of web applications.
- > Regularly utilize ReactJS including creating forms, managing events, using keys, creating routes, building dynamic reusable components, and incorporating redux for smart components.
- > Manage code branches via Beanstalk versioning software and deploy code to environments via Jenkins server deployment.

» Digital Marketing Manager

08/2015 - 11/2016

- > Developed the front-end of primary website through WordPress CMS with Software Engineer and increased incoming qualified leads by 40% over a four month period.
- > Designed and optimized online marketing & advertising campaigns via search marketing (SEO and PPC), email, and social media.

» Digital Marketing Coordinator 09/2013 - 08/2015

- > Designed responsive landing pages, email templates, banners, and other graphics for use in digital promotions and lead-generation.
- > Managed development schedule to optimize deliverability metrics through enterprise-level Marketing automation software.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

South Coast Surety

01/2018 - 11/2018

- > Designed and developed template-based Wordpress website working with backend developer.
 - > ENV: Wordpress/PHP, HTML, Sass, NPM

Mira Costa College Dance

01/2014 - 05/2014

- > Competed with team and won best web design implemented as new Dance Dept. Website.
 - > ENV: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Katie Scoggins Yoga

09/2014 - 12/2014

- > Designed and developed basic website for yoga teacher.
- > ENV: HTML, CSS, jQuery

EDUCATION

Mira Costa College

CSU, San Marcos

- > Programming with Python
- → E-Commerce & Web Presence → Mobile Sites & Apps
- > Site Design & Architecture

01/2014 - 12/2017

- > Web Design: PHP/Wordpress
- JavaScript and jQuery

08/2007 - 05/2012

- > B.S. Business Administration Global Business Management and Marketing, Minor German Language
 - > VP, CSUSM Marketing Society
- > Developed and implemented web, email, and social presence for 50 member club.